George S. Patton Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Family Papers, 1857-1979 (Box 14-24)
  - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Patton, George S. (1923- ) (son), 1939-1945, (4 folders)
    - Patton, Ruth Wilson (mother), 1904-1919
    - Wilson, Annie (aunt), 1904-1919, 1926-1928, (4 folders)
    - Other family members, 1905, 1917-1918, 1941-1945, undated, (2 folders)
  - Miscellany
    - Genealogical material, 1913, 1928, undated
    - Oddments, 1859-1860, 1918, 1943-1945
    - Patton, Beatrice Banning Ayer (wife)
      - Correspondence
        - Ayer, Ellen Barrows Banning and Frederick, 1916-1917
        - Condolence letters re Patton's death
          - Bound, 1945
          - Unbound, 1945-1946, (5 folders) (Box 22)
        - General
          - 1914-1919, 1925, 1943-1946, (15 folders)
          - 1947-1953, undated, (6 folders) (Box 23)
        - Patton, George S. (1856-1927) and Ruth Wilson, 1912-1919
        - Patton, George S. (1923- ), 1943-1946
        - Waters, Beatrice Patton (daughter), 1946
        - Wilson, Annie, 1902-1920, (3 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1910, 1942-1950, undated
    - Patton, George S. (1833-1864) (grandfather), 1864
    - Patton, George S. (1856-1927) (father)
      - Correspondence, 1902-1908, (2 folders)
      - "My Memories of Papa," by Patton, 1927
    - Patton, George S. (1923- ) (son), 1943-1949, 1972, 1979, (3 folders)
    - Patton, Ruth Wilson (mother), 1884, 1903-1904 (Box 24)
    - Smith, George H. (step-grandfather), 1857, 1867, 1873, 1905-1914, undated, (15 folders)
    - Totten, Ruth Ellen Patton (daughter), 1945-1946
- Correspondence, 1903-1945 (Box 25-45)
  Chronological, official, and topical correspondence, with attached and appended material, between Patton and his staff, army officials, friends, acquaintances, and the general public.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of correspondence and therein chronologically, although the topical correspondence is arranged alphabetically by topic and therein chronologically.
  - Chronological (Box 25)
    - 1903-1940, (19 folders)
    - 1941, (12 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1942
      - A-R, (11 folders)
      - S-Y, (4 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1943
      - A-S, (19 folders)
      - T-W See also Oversize (Box 28)
    - 1944
      - A-P, (16 folders)
      - Q-Y, (6 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1945
      - A-F, (12 folders)
      - G-P, (16 folders) (Box 30)
      - Q-Z, (13 folders) (Box 31)
  - Official
    - 1942
      - A-D, (4 folders)
      - E-W, (6 folders) (Box 32)
    - 1943
      - A-K, (14 folders)
      - L-W, (7 folders) (Box 33)
    - 1944
      - A-K, (13 folders)
      - L-W, (15 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1945
      - A-C, (6 folders)
      - D-W, (17 folders) (Box 35)
  - Topical
    - Casualty inquiries, 1943-1945
      - A-D, (3 folders)
      - E-Z, (12 folders) (Box 36)
    - Christmas and get-well greetings after automobile accident, 1945, (3 vols.); (1 vol.) (Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
    - Crank file, 1944-1945
    - Fan mail
      - 1943, (2 folders)
      - 1944
        - 1944, Jan.-Aug., (4 folders)
        - 1944, Sept.-Nov., (11 folders) (Box 40)
        - 1944, Dec., (3 folders) (Box 41)
      - 1945
        - 1945, Jan.-Apr., (11 folders)
        - 1945, May-Oct., (18 folders) (Box 42)
        - 1945, Nov.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 43)
      - Undated
    - Furloughs and discharges, 1943-1945, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous inquiries and requests, 1943-1945, (5 folders)
    - Slapping incidents, Sicily
      - Originals, 1943-1944
        - A-L, (4 folders)
        - M-W, (4 folders) (Box 44)
        - Unidentified, 1943
      - Typescripts, 1943-1944, (4 folders)
    - Thank you letters and acknowledgments
      - 1943, (3 folders)
      - 1944
        - 1944, Jan.-Oct., (3 folders)
  - Topical (Box 45)
    - Thank you letters and acknowledgments
      - 1944
        - 1944, Nov.-Dec., (2 folders)
      - 1945, (9 folders)
- Military Papers, 1903-1976 (Box 45-55)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, orders, citations, speeches, photographs, training instructions, policy and procedural material, Patton's personnel file, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically into three categories: administrative file, personnel "201" file, and subject file. The files within the categories are further arranged alphabetically by name of person, topic, or type of material, with the exception of the administrative file which is arranged chronologically.
  Includes two reels of microfilm of Patton's official personnel file, the originals of which are not in the collection. Shelf no. 17,250.
  - Administrative file (Box 45)
    - 1941-1942, (5 folders)
    - 1943
      - 1943, Jan.-June, (4 folders)
      - 1943, July-Dec. See also Oversize, (10 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1944 See also Oversize, (7 folders)
    - 1945, undated See also Oversize, (10 folders) (Box 47)
  - Personnel "201" file
    - Personal file kept by Patton
      - 1903-1932, (7 folders)
      - 1937-1943, (20 folders) (Box 48)
      - 1944-1945 See also Oversize, (11 folders) (Box 49)
  - United States Department of the Army records, Available only on microfilm. Two reels, shelf no. 17,250. Documents damaged in the St. Louis fire were placed in polyester film envelopes and interfiled chronologically before filming. (Reel 1)
    - Evaluations
      - Citations, commendations, decorations
        - 1918-1945, 1970, undated
      - Efficiency reports and efficiency file, 1918-1945
      - Ratings and memorandum records, 1917-1940
    - General
      - 1917-1957
      - 1961-1976, undated (Reel 2)
      - Punch cards change, International Business Machine Corp. records, 1938-1945
      - Report of change slips, 1919-1942
    - Medical records, 1904-1948, undated
  - Subject file
    - Airborne troops, investigation into friendly fire incident by ground troops, 1943, 1944
    - Bastogne operation, 1944-1945 See also Oversize
    - Casualty information
      - General, 1944-1945, (3 folders)
      - Reports
        - 1944
          - 1944, Aug., (2 folders)
          - 1944, Sept.-Dec., (8 folders) (Box 50)
        - 1945, (9 folders)
    - Cavalry, 1926-1931, undated, (2 folders)
    - Citations, 1944-1945, (5 folders) (Box 51)
    - Death and funeral of Patton, 1945-1946, (2 folders)
    - Denazification of Germany, 1945, (3 folders)
    - Displaced persons, 1945, (3 folders)
    - Financial papers (Box 52)
      - 1917, (8 folders)
      - 1943-1945, (3 folders)
    - Flint, Harry Albert ("Paddy"), 1944
    - French Second Division, 1944, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders)
    - G-3 (operations)
      - Overlays, 1943 See Oversize
      - Reports, 1943, (2 folders)
    - German generals, captured, interviews, 1944-1945
    - Liberation of Paris, France, and other cities and towns, 1944-1945 (Box 53)
    - Maneuver impressions, 1940
    - Miscellany
      - 1917-1935, 1943-1945 See also Oversize, (4 folders)
    - Press, 1944-1945, undated, (2 folders)
    - Second Armored Division
      - General, 1940
      - Training memoranda, 1940-1942
    - Tanks
      - Christie tank and tactical papers notebook, 1926-1929
      - Drawings, 1919 (Box 54)
      - General, 1917-1920, 1930-1931, 1941-1944, undated See also Oversize, (9 folders)
      - Mechanical features, 1918-1919
      - Photograph albums See also Container 61, World War I
        - 1916-1931, (3 folders)
        - 1918-1919 (Box 55)
      - Reports
        - General, 1917-1919, (3 folders)
        - Officer reports from personal experience, 1918, (2 folders)
      - Tactics, 1929-1931, 1941-1942, (4 folders)
- Military Library, 1907-1947 (Box 56-58)
  Reports, printed matter, near-print material, and typed notes.
  - 1907-1927, (9 folders) (Box 56)
  - 1930-1944 See also Oversize, (10 folders) (Box 57)
  - 1945-1947, undated, (9 folders) (Box 58)
- Maps, 1906-1945 (Box 59-60)
  Maps from various phases of Patton's military career.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and therein chronologically.
  - Miscellaneous, 1906, 1913 See Oversize (Box 59)
  - World War I, 1918 See also Oversize
  - World War II
    - European theater
      - Situation maps
        - 1944, (12 folders)
        - 1945, (8 folders) (Box 60)
      - Third army unit, operations, 1944-1945 See Oversize
    - Germany, road maps, 1944-1945 See Oversize
    - Miscellany, 1943-1945, undated See also Oversize
- Photographs, 1864-1958 (Box 60-64)
  Bound and unbound photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Early career (Box 60)
    - Fort Bliss, Tex., 1915-1916
    - Fort Meade, Md., 1919-1920 See also Oversize
    - Mexican Punitive Expedition, 1916-1917
    - Miscellany, 1920-1925
    - Olympics, 1912
    - United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1909
  - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
    - 1864, 1893, 1930, 1939, 1950-1958, undated See also Oversize, (7 folders)
  - World War I, 1917-1918 See also Containers 54-55, Photograph albums, (3 folders)
  - World War II (Box 62)
    - Albums See Oversize
    - Unbound photographs
      - Concentration camps, 1945, (3 folders)
      - Europe, 1944-1945, (15 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1945, undated, (6 folders) (Box 63)
      - North Africa, 1942
      - Sicily
        - 1943, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 64)
        - circa 1943-circa 1944, (3 folders)
- Speeches and Writings File, 1900-1947 (Box 64-74)
  Holograph, typescript, near-print, and published copies of articles, speeches, lectures, book reviews, memoranda, reports, field manuals, instructional material, poetry, and memoirs.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Book, War As I Knew It (1947) (Box 64)
    - Appendices and notes
    - Corrected typescript, (4 folders)
    - Draft, (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 65)
    - General
    - Published copy
  - General (Box 66)
    - Index, partial, undated
    - Texts
      - 1900-1917, (12 folders)
      - 1918, (6 folders) (Box 67)
      - 1919
        - 1919, Jan.
        - 1919, Feb., (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 68)
        - 1919, Apr.-Oct., (3 folders)
      - 1920-1927, (7 folders)
      - 1928-1930 See also Oversize, (12 folders) (Box 69)
      - 1931-1935, (12 folders) (Box 70)
      - 1936-1943, undated, (13 folders) (Box 71)
  - Notebooks and notes (Box 72)
    - 1905-1931, (9 folders)
    - 1933-1941, undated, (9 folders) (Box 73)
  - Poetry (Box 74)
    - By Patton
      - Notebook of texts, 1916-1921
      - Unbound texts, 1903-1927, 1943-1945, undated, (5 folders)
    - By others, 1918, 1944-1945, undated
  - Research material
    - German military methods, 1934-1939
    - Miscellany, 1929-1931
- Miscellany, 1911-1966 (Box 74-75)
  Memoranda, reports, biographical information, citations, certificates, photographs, near-print and printed matter, notes and notebooks, postcards, and newspaper clippings.
  Arranged by name of person or organization, topic, or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Biographical information, 1943, 1953, undated (Box 74)
  - Fencing, swordsmanship, Mounted Service School, Fort Riley, Kans., 1911-1915, undated, (4 folders)
  - Koch, Oscar W., 1966 (Box 75)
  - Medals and other honors, 1918, 1925, 1943-1951, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders)
  - Oddments, 1918, 1928-1931, 1943-1947, 1961-1966, undated See also Oversize, (4 folders)
  - Olympics, 1912, (2 folders)
  - Patton Hall, Fort Riley, Kans., 1946
  - Patton Museum, Armored Center, Fort Knox, Ky., 1948-1949
  - Postcards, 1945, undated
  - Printed matter, 1916-1917, 1942-1945, 1963-1966, undated
- Manuscript Material Removed from Scrapbooks After Microfilming, 1807-1950 (Box 76-78)
  Correspondence, photographs, certificates, calling cards, and other material retained after microfilming. Once the scrapbooks were microfilmed, the volumes, OV 23-OV 49, were destroyed.
  - Vols. OV 23-OV 27, 1807, 1877, 1899, 1908, 1917-1919, 1932-1934, 1944-1950, undated See also Oversize, (7 folders) (Box 76)
  - Vols. OV 28-OV 34, 1941-1942 See also Oversize, (8 folders) (Box 77)
  - Vols. OV 35-OV 49, 1939-1946 See also Oversize, (14 folders) (Box 78)
- Oversize, 1807-1951 (Box OV 1-OV 50)
  Oversize material consisting of maps, diagrams and blueprints, overlays, photographs, charts, posters, a report, and scrapbooks.
  Organized and described according to the series from which the items were removed. Scrapbooks constitute a separate grouping within the oversize series.
  Scrapbooks OV 23-OV 49 are available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 21,850.
  - Chronological File (Box OV 1)
    - 1918
      - 1918, Apr.-May (Container 8)
      - 1918, Sept. (Container 8)
      - 1918, Nov. (Container 9)
    - 1919
      - 1919, Jan. (Container 9)
    - 1936 (Container 10)
    - 1942
      - 1942, Oct. (Container 10)
    - 1944
      - 1944, July-Aug. (Container 12)
      - 1944, Oct. (Container 12)
    - 1945
      - 1945, Dec. (Container 14)
  - Correspondence (Box OV 2)
    - Chronological
      - 1943
        - T-W (Container 28)
  - Military Papers
    - Administrative file
      - 1943
        - 1943, July (Container 46)
        - 1943, Nov. (Container 46)
      - 1944
        - 1944, Sept. (Container 46)
      - 1945
        - 1945, Jan.-Mar. (Container 47)
        - 1945, Nov.-Dec. (Container 47)
    - Personnel "201" file
      - Personal file kept by Patton
        - 1945, Jan. (Container 49)
    - Subject file
      - Bastogne operation, 1945 (Container 49)
      - French Second Division, 1944, undated (Container 52)
      - G-3 (operations) (Box OV 3)
        - Overlays
          - 1943
            - 1943, July (Container 52)
            - 1943, Aug.-Nov. (Container 52) (Box OV 4)
      - Miscellany, 1945, May (Container 53) (Box OV 5)
      - Tanks
        - General
          - [1918] (Container 54)
          - 1941 (Container 54)
  - Military library (Box OV 6)
    - 1943 (Container 57)
  - Maps (Box OV 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1906, 1913 (Container 59)
    - World War I, 1918 (Container 59)
    - World War II (Box OV 8)
      - European theater
        - Third army unit, operations, 1944-1945 (Container 60)
      - Germany, road maps, 1944-1945 (Container 60) (Box OV 9)
      - Miscellany, undated (Container 60)
  - Photographs (Box OV 10)
    - Early career
      - Fort Meade, Md., 1919-1920 (Container 60)
    - Miscellaneous, 1951 (Container 61)
    - World War II (Box OV 11)
      - Albums (Container 62)
        - 1941-1945
        - 1942-1943 (Box OV 12)
        - 1942-1943 (Box OV 13)
        - 1943 (Box OV 14)
        - 1943 (Box OV 15)
        - 1943-1944 (Box OV 16)
        - 1944 (Box OV 17)
        - 1944-1945 (Box OV 18)
        - 1944-1946 (Box OV 19)
        - 1944-1947 (Box OV 20)
        - 1945 (Box OV 21)
  - Speeches and writings file (Box OV 22)
    - General
      - 1928, Jan. (Container 69)
  - Miscellany
    - Medals and other honors
      - 1943-1945 (Container 75)
  - Oddments, 1944 (Container 75)
  - Scrapbooks, Containers OV 23-OV 49 are available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 21,850. (Box OV 23, Reel 1)
    - 1807, 1944-1945
    - 1877, 1940-1950 (Box OV 24, Reel 1)
    - 1899-1929, undated (Box OV 25, Reel 2)
    - 1914-1934 (Box OV 26, Reel 2)
    - 1916 (Box OV 27, Reel 2)
    - 1938-1942 (Box OV 28, Reel 2)
    - 1940-1941 (Box OV 29, Reel 2)
    - 1941-1942 (Box OV 30, Reel 2)
    - 1941-1943 (Box OV 31, Reel 3)
    - 1942 (Box OV 32, Reel 3)
    - 1942 (Box OV 33, Reel 3)
    - 1942 (Box OV 34, Reel 3)
    - 1942-1943 (Box OV 35, Reel 3)
    - 1942-1943 (Box OV 36, Reel 3)
    - 1942-1943 (Box OV 37, Reel 4)
    - 1942-1944 (Box OV 38, Reel 4)
    - 1943 (Box OV 39, Reel 4)
    - 1943 (Box OV 40, Reel 4)
    - 1943 (Box OV 41, Reel 5)
    - 1943 (Box OV 42, Reel 5)
    - 1943 (Box OV 43, Reel 5)
    - 1943-1944 (Box OV 44, Reel 5)
    - 1943-1944 (Box OV 45, Reel 5)
    - 1943-1946 (Box OV 46, Reel 5)
    - 1944 (Box OV 47, Reel 6)
    - 1944-1945 (Box OV 48, Reel 6)
    - 1944-1945 (Box OV 49, Reel 7)
  - Oversize manuscript material removed from scrapbooks after microfilming, 1941-1945 (Containers 76-78) (Box OV 50, Reel 7)